<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>[ Y k N x ]</title>
    <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on [ Y k N x ]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 17:45:50 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//yknx4.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s no gender violence at all</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/theres-no-gender-violence-at-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 17:45:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/theres-no-gender-violence-at-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know today is the Women&amp;rsquo;s Day and &lt;strong&gt;this ain&amp;rsquo;t a day to celebrate but to commemorate all those women that have fought for women&amp;rsquo;s rights&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even though I agree with that, I still feel uneasy due to the fact that &lt;strong&gt;gender violence against men is usually not addressed&lt;/strong&gt;, at least not the same way and things get worse when you talk about non-traditional genders. And so sometimes I feel these kind of commemoration isn&amp;rsquo;t fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then in all the flow of posts about the international women&amp;rsquo;s day I saw this pic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://yknx4.github.io/blog/images/gender_violence.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;alt text&#34; title=&#34;No Gender Violence&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It says &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;there no such a thing as gender violence, gender itself is violence&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;.
And then everything clicked, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;root&lt;/strong&gt; of all gender violence is &lt;strong&gt;gender itself&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue is for boys, Pink is for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short hair for boys, Long hair for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pants for boys, Skirts for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rude for boys, Cute for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sports is for boys, Dance is for girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people still live with this guidelines their lifes, even worse teach their kids that&amp;rsquo;s how they are supposed to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s the problem, since we were kids we were taught (at least that&amp;rsquo;s in Mexico) that girls have to be soft, cute, and fragile while boys have to be tough, rude, and strong. And so the stereotypes of a weak girl and a strong boy were buried on our enviroment, society, and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these were the reason 60 years ago, women were not allowed to vote, to work, to ask, to choose, to everything. And lots and lots of womens fought to overcome this, those women are the women we commemorate in this days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the same &lt;em&gt;guidelines&lt;/em&gt; removing the gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue is for persons, Pink is for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short hair for persons, Long hair for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pants for persons, Skirts for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rude for persons, Cute for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sports is for persons, Dance is for persons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If society lived with this, there would never be a comparison between, there would never be sterotypes, there would be only persons, no weak girls, no strong boys only persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limiting how a person is supposed to be just because of the fact that he was born with or without something between the legs it&amp;rsquo;s really stupid. And sadly these days most of this still holds true, when it cames to non cisgender persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a &lt;strong&gt;boy wants to be pretty&lt;/strong&gt;, put on makeup and wear a skirt, or a &lt;strong&gt;girl wants to look rude&lt;/strong&gt;, have short hair and wear saggy pants, &lt;strong&gt;Gender violence is still there&lt;/strong&gt;. Even when nowadays everyone is fine with girls wearing the once male-only clothes &lt;em&gt;pants&lt;/em&gt;, a boy wearing a skirt is treated as obscene, dirty, perverted, etc&amp;hellip; and I don&amp;rsquo;t see people commemorating boy&amp;rsquo;s day, or Male&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt; movement fighting for gender equality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s stop fighting Gender Violence, and let&amp;rsquo;s figth Gender itself. We got to remove all these sterotypes. Let&amp;rsquo;s not fight for women&amp;rsquo;s rights, let&amp;rsquo;s figth for &lt;strong&gt;REAL&lt;/strong&gt; human rights. Rights that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t discriminate by sex nor gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me when i say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we get rid of Genders, we get rid of all gender issues. Including violence&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hello world!</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 09:19:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/article/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-this-blog:6f2f4d58d486b2f9d96fea371fa23b59&#34;&gt;About this blog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is the first post, and as every programmer&amp;rsquo;s first time. It has to start with a Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a professional blogger nor a writer nor a native english speaker. Expect some idle days, expect some &lt;em&gt;unproffesional&lt;/em&gt; posts, and expect lots and lots of silly english mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;who-am-i:6f2f4d58d486b2f9d96fea371fa23b59&#34;&gt;Who am i?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look the &lt;a href=&#34;//yknx4.github.io/blog/about/&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-this-and-what-this-is-not-about:6f2f4d58d486b2f9d96fea371fa23b59&#34;&gt;What is this and what this is &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; about&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may become a technology blog, this will include for sure some development posts. But after all, this is a Personal blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I may post about my life, my ideas, my opinions, my personal thoughts and my controverted stance on some already controverted topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to comment everything (as soon as i enable comments), I&amp;rsquo;m open to hear other&amp;rsquo;s opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And well&amp;hellip;. welcome to this place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>//yknx4.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 17:34:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//yknx4.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal-background:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Personal Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-myself:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;About myself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;me:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;me&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m Jorge Alejandro Figueroa Perez, sometimes just &lt;strong&gt;Jorge&lt;/strong&gt;, sometimes just &lt;strong&gt;Alejandro&lt;/strong&gt;, sometimes just &lt;strong&gt;Ale&lt;/strong&gt; and in the Internet most of the times I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;Yknx&lt;/strong&gt; (Except on some sites where some asian dude got the nickname first).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a supporter of &lt;strong&gt;Social Freedom&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Internet Rights&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;LGBT&lt;/strong&gt; Community. I have the opinion that &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;everyone can and shall live however the f*ck they want&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; as long as they don&amp;rsquo;t harm anyone else&amp;rsquo;s freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think any society should be free of oppresion, and have all their human rights assured regardless of ther political, religious, sexual, or whatever position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think all those rights should be also preserved and enforced in all the modern enviroments that are constantly surging in the Internet. (Yep, This means that you should also be able to do whatever you want on the Internet)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;against Gender Roles&lt;/em&gt; (a byproduct of sexism), I don&amp;rsquo;t think a person can be defined by what society tells them they are supposed to be just because the person was born with or without something between the legs. I consider myself &lt;em&gt;genderless&lt;/em&gt; or even better &lt;em&gt;Allgendersatthesametime-ish gender&lt;/em&gt;, so feel free to address me however you feel you should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live in this &lt;em&gt;unique&lt;/em&gt; place called &lt;strong&gt;Colima&lt;/strong&gt; in this &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt;
country called &lt;strong&gt;Mexico&lt;/strong&gt;, and I have been living here for about all my life. [Except for the 6 months I gladly had the opportunity to live in &lt;strong&gt;South Korea&lt;/strong&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;myself:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;myself&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love to read everything about tech, and I try to hack every
single gadget in my hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I have a router with
tomato-wrt working as my personal server, and customized
roms on my Android devices, I also enjoy the music, and have played guitar for about 10 years, but
mostly as a casual hobby and not as a professional guitarist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of Korean and Japanese culture, I had for about 5 years a University club about it, so I learned and researched a lot about it, also I lived 6 months in South Korea and been a few times too Japan. So I got to experience the real thing at least for a short time, and I came to love it even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;language-learning:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Language Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love languages, i really like to learn languages, as now I can handle these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spanish&lt;/strong&gt;: [I&amp;rsquo;m Mexican so&amp;hellip;.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;: [Good enough for living and working - Cambride FCE B2]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Korean&lt;/strong&gt;: [Been learning for 2 years, I have a basic level, 난 한국말을 항상 연습 한 중인데 당신이 연습도 하고 하고 싶으하면 매시지를 보내 주세요]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Japanese&lt;/strong&gt;: [This is the half of my first year, so I suck pretty much :P]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;professional-background:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Professional Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;development:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Engineer&lt;/strong&gt; student with strong Development Abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am deeply interested on mobile development for &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt;,
Desktop Applications on &lt;strong&gt;.NET&lt;/strong&gt;, and web development,
especially in newer and promising technologies like &lt;strong&gt;Nodejs&lt;/strong&gt;,
&lt;strong&gt;MongoDB&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Ruby/Rails&lt;/strong&gt;, etc…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been playing with programming since Secondary
School, and have tried multiple languages and platforms. So
far liking Javascript/Node.js, C#/.NET and Java/Android the
most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enviroment:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Enviroment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mostly work on &lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt; and recently &lt;strong&gt;OSX&lt;/strong&gt; but I can move freely on &lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt; based
environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brackets for NodeJS and web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MacDown for Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android Studio well&amp;hellip;. for Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio for .NET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RubyMine for Ruby (At least until I have my Student License ㅠㅠ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Atom and SublimeText are my backups when something else fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;magmalabs-intern-2016-now:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;MagmaLabs - Intern (2016 - now)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I&amp;rsquo;m doing my internship as a developer in MagmaLabs, working with Ruby/Rails, Javascript (this time AngularJS) and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beanstack (Library web application in Ruby/Rails)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MagmaRooms (Android Application for Google Calendar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;school-projects-university-of-colima-2012-2015:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;School Projects - University of Colima (2012 - 2015)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though most school projects sucks, and we all know it, I did multiple
school projects in which I  have practiced all my learnt
knowledge. Some of them are available on my GitHub repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;information-retrieval-engine-school-project-university-of-korea-march-2016-june-2016:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Information Retrieval Engine (School Project) - University of Korea (March 2016 - June 2016)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had plenty of fun with this project, it was the first time i had
to work with proper Math models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to program a Information
Retrieval engine for web documents that calculates similarity
based on a query and displays relevant documents (an
archaic search engine), I did the processing in .NET and
showed the results in a web page made on Express.js/Node.js
with all the information stored in MySQL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;education-background:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Education Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;8th-semester-of-bachelor-degree-in-software-engineering-university-of-colima-2012-now:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;8th semester of Bachelor Degree in Software Engineering, University of Colima (2012- Now)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;exchange-student-program-university-of-korea-spring-semester-2015:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Exchange Student Program, University of Korea (Spring semester, 2015)&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>